It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Hanzō was thought to be dead, but he joined hands with mysterious Shianui clan and is looking to kill Ieyasu again.
죽었다 생각됐던 한조는 의문의 일족 시라누이와 손을 잡아 다시 이에야스의 명줄을 노린다.
Musashi and others has managed to prevent Ieyasu from being assassinated, and according to the map that Hanzō dropped,
이에야스의 암살을 미연에 방지한 무사시 일행은 남겨진 지도를 단서로
they go on a journey to Kyushu to take Hanzō down.
한조를 쓰러뜨리기 위해 규슈에 여행을 떠났다.
Mr. Saigo is
사이고 씨는
a Mysterious Person
수수께끼의 인물이오
(Shinagawa-shuku: shuku is a type of historical Japanese station/inn, and Shinagawa-shuku was one of the Four Edo Inns Satsuma-kuni: A past province in Saikai Circuit, now Kagoshima)
(시나가와슈쿠: 일본의 역참 중 하나로 에도 사(4)숙의 하나 사츠마 국(國): 사이카이도에 있던 일본의 옛 율령국)
This is Shinagawa-juku. Musashi and others are going to get a boat ride to Satsumania at Kyushu.
여긴 시나가와슈쿠. 무사시 일행은 여기서 규슈의 사츠마니아 행 배를 타고자 하고 있었다.
But!
그렇지만!
The next boat departs in night-dasu... I should have eaten my last meal slower if I knew that-dasu...
뭣이오, 이번 배는 밤에 떠나오... 그럼 조금 더 느긋하게 먹었으면 좋았을 걸 그랬소.
Hmph, do you know what they say from the past? A martial artist who rushes is unsightly.
흥, 오래 전부터 그러지. 성질 급한 무예가는 보기 흉하다고.
You always make a big fuss right before you have to go out.
넌 맨날 떠나기 직전이 되서야 우당탕탕 거리니 말이지.
You were like that ever since I met you.
지금까지 맨날 그랬던 너 말이다.
Hey, Musashi, you're embarassing me! Get up!
좀, 무사시, 창피하니까 일어나!
No matter what you say, I couldn't eat my meal since I was in hurry...
그런 소리를 해도, 나 서둘렀으니까 밥도 못 먹어서...
Let's treat him as if we don't know him.
모르는 사람 치자.
Osenchan is cold too...
오센짱도 차가워...
People, I'm holding a dango quick eating contest as a shop opening event!
자, 자, 개점 서비스인 단고 빨리 먹기 콩쿠르입니다!
What?! Dango quick eating contest?!
뭐라?! 단고 빨리 먹기?!
He's so quick only at times like this.
이럴 때만은 잽싸다니까.
OPEN
오픈
Welcome to dango quick eating contest! Would anybody want to attempt?
자, 단고 빨리 먹기 콩쿠르입니다! 누구 도전할 사람 없나요!
If you eat 100 lines of dango before this hourglass runs out, it's free!
이 모래시계의 모래가 떨어질 때까지 단고 100줄을 먹으면 값은 무료.
You're also gonna get 300 mons in addition!
덤으로, 300문의 용돈도 받습니다!
Any participants?
자, 누구 해 볼 사람 없습니까!
I'll try that-dasu!
내가 도전하오!
Musashi! Why are you here?!
무사시. 네가 왜 여기에?!
Huh? Do you know me-dasu?
어? 나 알고 있소?
Well, I never saw a handsome boy like you until now!
글쎄, 난 너같은 잘생긴 아이는 처음 보네!
I knew it-dasu!
역시 그렇소.
Yeah, right!
그렇고말고!
Then let me eat-dasu! Bring it on-dasu!
그럼 잘 먹겠소! 팍팍 가지고 오시오!
T- then let's begin.
그, 그럼 시작합니다.
Ready, go!
준비, 땅!
Next!
다음!
For a martial artist, he's trying his best to be disgraceful.
무예가 주제에 되는 한껏 창피한 놈이군.
You can do it, Musashi! Let's have a dango party if you win!
힘내, 무사시! 상금 받으면 축하로 다 같이 단고 먹자!
Damn, he's such an extreme eater!
제기랄, 잘도 쳐먹네!
He'll even eat up my store that I manged to open at last!
진짜, 이렇게는 힘들게 연 가게까지 먹혀버리겠네!
Hey, you're almost there!
어이, 좀만 더 먹으면 100줄이야!
This leaves me no choice!
이렇게 된 바 최후의 수단이다!
(Tengu: An imaginary monster that has a long/high nose and a red face, and can fly. A depiction of Western/European people.)
(텐구: 얼굴이 붉고 코가 높으며/길며 하늘을 날 수 있다는 상상의 괴물. 과거 동양인의 서양인(유럽인) 얼굴 표현.)
Look! A Tengu has hit a tree and it's nosebleeding!
어! 텐구가 나무에 부딪혀서 코피 흘리고 있어!
Where, where?!
어디, 어디?!
And now 300 mons are mine!
이걸로 300문은 내 것!
And that's it!
네, 거기까지!
Look, time's up!
자, 시간이 다 됐어요.
Huh, I thought it still had a lot to go just before...
어라, 아까까진 아직 많이 남아 있었다고 생각했는데...
Well, that's too bad for you! I'll take 300 mons from whoever couldn't eat 'em all!
네, 안타깝습니다! 다 먹지 못한 사람에게선 300문을 가져갑니다!
What, 300 mons?! I never heard I had to pay for that...
어, 300문?! 나, 나, 돈 내야 한다고는 못 들었소...
What are you talking about? It's obvious that you have to pay if you couldn't eat them all!
무슨 소릴! 다 못 먹으면 돈 내는 건 상식이잖아요?
Hey, give me your money.
어이, 돈 내쇼.
I don't have that much money-dasu...
나, 그런 큰 돈 없소...
Hey, Kojirō!
아, 코지로!
I'm sorry, but can I borrow your money-dasu?
미안하지만 돈 빌려주면 좋겠소!
I refuse.
거절한다.
Hey, why is that-dasu?
에, 왜이오?
This is all your fault, for participating in a quick eating competition.
그런 빨리 먹기 대회 따위에 나간 네 잘못이다.
You take care of this.
알아서 해.
Please! Isn't it a good enough-dasu?
그런! 괜찮지 않소?
Hey, hey, hey, hey?
저기, 저기, 저기, 저기?
Don't act like a brat.
어리광 피우지 마라.
Tch. Cheapskate.
치. 구두쇠.
Cheapskate?!
구두쇠라고?!
Base cheapskate! (do-kechi)
순 구두쇠!
Base cheapskate?!
순 구두쇠?!
I despise being called a cheapskate more than everything else in this world! And then you put base(do-) there?!
난 노랭이라고 불리는 게 이 세상에서 제일 싫다! 그걸로 모자라서 순을 붙여?!
I'm telling you're a cheapskate because you are one-dasu!
구두쇠니까 구두쇠라고 말할 뿐이오!
You said that again, you dumbass(doji)!
또 그 소리 했겠다! 이 숙맥!
You dared to put bass(do) there!
"숙"을 붙였겠소, "숙"을!
Hey, just pay, will you?!
어이, 내라면 내!
Uh, you know...
아, 저 그게...
No need to pay-gowasu.
낼 필요는 없다.
Who the heck are you?!
뭐야, 넌!
My name is Saigo-gowasu.
난 사이고라 하는 자다.
Saigo
사이고
I was looking at you for a while, and I know you're cheating-gowasu.
아까부터 보고 있었고 자네는 꾀를 부리고 있다.
D- don't fool around! You have no evidence for that!
이, 이상한 소리 마라! 어디에 그런 증거가 있냐!
Hey, that hourglass!
아, 저 모래시계!
-Huh, huh?! -You fooled me!
-어, 어? -잘도 속였겠소!
Hey, don't do that!
아, 하지 마!
Hey, you must be Jiraiyan!
아, 너는 지라이얀!
As you've found out, it can't be helped! That's bye to you, Musashi!
들켰으니 어쩔 수 없군! 안녕이다, 무사시!
Hey, stop, Jiraiyan!
아, 멈추시오, 지라이얀!
Damn! I'll take it out on you next time I see you-dasu!
젠장, 다음에 보면 혼쭐내 주겠소!
Thank you so much for helping.
도와 주어서 정말 고맙소.
No problem-gowasu. I despise dishonest things, so I couldn't just watch people being deceived-gowasu.
아무렴 좋다. 난 부정한 일은 몹시 싫으니 속는 모습을 그대로 두고 볼 수는 없었다.
Let's go, too.
자, 우리도 가자.
Base cheapskate.
왕짠돌이.
You two, what happened?
어? 왜 그래, 둘 다.
I do not want to travel with a cruel bastard like him anymore-dasu.
나, 이런 박정한 놈하고는 더는 같이 여행하고 싶지 않소.
My pride also do not forgive me from being with a fickle guy like this.
저도 이런 경박한 자와 함께 있는 건 자존심이 용서하지 못합니다.
Fickle?! You are even more cruel and cheap!
경박한 자라? 그 쪽이야말로 박정한 구두쇠이오!
How dare you say that again?!
또 그 소리 했겠다, 이게!
You guys! It's not a time for you to quarrel! We are about to penetrate into the base of the enemy!
에휴, 너희들 지금 싸우고 있을 때가 아니잖아? 우린 이제 막 적의 본거지에 쳐들어가려던 참이잖아!
That Shiranui Clan has nothing to do with me-dasu! My only objective is to become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
시라누이 일족 따위 나하고는 관계 없소! 내 목표는 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되는 일 뿐이오!
Same for me too!
나도 그렇다!
Oh, is that so? So that was your ulterior motive! I see! You guys do not matter to me anymore!
아, 그러셔? 너희 그럴 생각이었네? 그래! 이제 너희 따위는!
I'll go Satsumania by myself and annihilate Shiranui Clan all by myself!
혼자 사츠마니아에 쳐들어가서 시라누이 일족 전멸시켜 줄 테니까!
Hmph!
흥!
Please wait, Senhime!
아, 기다려 주십시오, 센히메 님!
Hime!
히메!
Hmph.
흥.
Princess!
공주님!
Princess, princess! Please wait for me! That before was nothing more than tit for tat!
공주님, 공주님! 기다려 주세요! 아까 말은 오는 말에 가는 말이었습니다!
I was not serious when I was saying that!
절대 본심이 아닙니다!
Be quiet. Just don't follow me like that!
시끄러워. 끈덕지게 따라오지 마!
Please wait, Senhime!
기다려 주세요, 센히메 님!
A pervert!
치한이야!
What, a pervert?
어, 치한?
What? A pervert?
어디? 치한이라고?
So you are a pervert!
너냐! 그 자식이!
-Err... -Help! This guy is a pervert!
-어... -아앍! 살려줘! 변태야, 이 남자 놈!
Nononono, I'm not a pervert!
아니아니아니, 저는 치한이 아닙니다.
-I'm not a pervert... -You liar! You're gonna get bald if you act like that!
-치한이 아닙... -거짓말쟁이! 음란한 생각하다간 대머리 된다!
Be obedient and follow us!
얌전히 따라와라!
S- stop! I'm not a pervert! Stop, stop!
그, 그만둬! 치, 치한 아니야! 그만, 그만!
Senhime!
센히메 님!
What were they thinking?! I'll show that I don't need their protection as I can take Shiranui Clan down by myself!
뭐야, 뭐야, 뭐야! 걔들도 참, 저런 녀석들한테 보호받지 않아도 충분히 혼자서 시라누이 일족 따위 때려눕혀 주겠어!
Hey, hurry up! This way!
어이, 서둘러라! 여기다!
Hurry up, hurry!
어이어이, 서둘러라, 서둘러!
That must be a ninja of Shiranui.
저건 시라누이 닌자?
SHIRANUI
시라누이
I wonder what they are carrying.
쟤들 뭘 옮기는 걸까?
DANGER
위험
N- no way...
이, 이건...
Tch, what are wrong with Osenchan and Kojirō-dasu?! I hate whoever gets angry so easily-dasu!
칫, 뭣이오, 뭣이오! 오센짱도 코지로도! 쉽사리 화내는 놈들은 난 싫소!
But still... I'm worried-dasu. Shiranui Clan is told to be a strong enemy, too.
그래도... 괜찮을지 모르겠소. 시라누이 일족은 강적이라 하고...
No, that has nothing to do with me-dasu.
아니아니, 나하고는 관계 없는 일이오.
I have an objective to become the number one martial artist of Jipangu!
나는 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 될 목표가 있소!
Hey! Mr. Saigo!
아! 사이고 씨!
Wha-?!
어?!
This is Shiranui's coat-dasu!
이건 시라누이의 문장이오!
There's something with this-dasu.
이건 수상하오.
Mister, would you like one?
손님, 하나 어떠십니까?
Let me see.
어디 보자.
This is an exquisite one-gowasu.
오, 이건 꽤 진귀한 것이군.
You have an eye for these.
역시 안목이 있으십니다.
So, could you get into contact with him-gowasu?
그래서 그 쪽하고는 연락이 되었나?
Yessir. He said he's waiting at that place.
예, 그 곳에서 기다린다고 하셨습니다.
I see.
그렇군.
Would you like to use this dish as your bowl, Shiro?
이 접시를 먹이접시로 할까, 시로?
Hahaha, I see. You don't like it-gowasu.
하하하, 그래, 마음에 안 드는구나.
-Maybe next time, then-gowasu. -Understood!
-그럼 다음 기회에. -예, 그리 알지요!
It's getting even more suspicious-dasu.
점점 수상해지오.
Senhime!
센히메 님!
Senhime! Senhime!
센히메 님! 센히메 님!
Hey! Who do you think I am?!
이 자식! 이 나를 누구라 생각하나!
I am the granddaughter of General Ieyasu, Senhime! Release me this instance!
제너럴 이에야스의 손녀 센히메다! 당장 포승을 풀어라!
Aren't you a vigorous girl, for being captured.
허, 잡혀 있는 주제에 활기찬 여자군.
What are you going to do to me?
이 날 어쩔 셈이야?
As you've seen the load over there, you will not go back alive.
저 짐을 본 이상 살아서 돌아갈 수는 없아.
We'll make you into a lump of cement and sink into Edo Bay.
시멘트 덩이로 만들어서 에도 만에 가라앉혀 주겠다.
What?!
어?
Musashi and others has split among friends.
자기들끼리 분열해버린 무사시 일행.
Will Senhime Survive? And what about the mysterious man Saigo?
과연 센히메의 명은, 그리고 수수께끼의 사내 사이고의 정체는?
Wait for the stormy latter half!
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
He doesn't look like a bad guy at all-dasu...
이렇게 보고 있으면 전혀 악인으로는 안 보이오...
Really suspicious-dasu.
역시 수상하오.
Who's there-gowasu?
누구냐!
meow... meow...
야옹... 야옹...
A cat, eh?
고양이군.
meow...
야옹...
Senhime!
센히메 님!
Where did she disappear to?
대체 어디에 가 버렸나...
SHIRANUI
시라누이
That is Shiranui's coat.
저건 분명 시라누이의 문장.
Where are you transporting all those weapons to?
저만큼의 무기를 어디에 가져간다는 거야?
Hmph, that information won't help you since you're going to die.
흥, 죽을 주제에 그런 걸 알아봤자 소용없지.
And that's why you can tell me the reason!
죽을 거니까 알려줘도 상관 없잖아?
Well, that makes sense! Listen and be surprised! To Satsumania!
뭐, 그것도 그렇지. 듣고 놀라라! 사츠마니아에!
And what are you going to do with these at Satsumania?
사츠마니아에 가져가서 어쩌려고?
Hmph, isn't that obvious? Taking over Satsumania will be the first step of taking over the whole Jipangu.
흥, 뻔한 일을. 지팡국을 수중에 넣기 위해서 사츠마니아 정복으로 시작하는 것이지.
What?! I, Senhime, cannot forgive that!
뭐라고? 그런 건 이 센히메가 용서 못한다!
Why don't you explain what can you do when you can't move?
허, 손발도 꼼짝 못하는 주제에 뭘 할 수 있단 거냐?
Just you see. Anything can happen to you guys, since my precious comrades are coming to save me!
두고 봐라. 지금 너희들이 어떻게 되어도 몰라. 소중한 동료가 구해주러 올 테니까!
Hmph, you'll become a cement lump before that!
헤, 그 전에 넌 시멘트덩이다!
Musashi! Kojirō!
무사시! 코지로!
Who's that?!
누구냐!
Senhime. I'm here to save you!
센히메 님. 구하러 왔습니다.
Kojirō!
코지로!
How impudent of you, trying to defy us?!
에잇, 우리에게 대들다니 건방지다!
Get him!
잡아라!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
비검 츠바메가에시!
That's as far as you go, you brat!
거기까지다, 꼬맹아!
What?!
뭐야?!
Whatever Tsubamegaeshi is, it can't defeat this.
츠바메가에시가 어떤 기술이든 이걸 이길 수는 없지.
That's cowardly!
비겁하다!
Put your sword down like a good boy.
자, 순순히 칼을 내려놓아라.
Kojirō!
코지로!
Damn!
젠장!
That person surely walks well-dasu. I don't feel my legs already-dasu.
이거 원, 잘 걷는 사람이오. 난 이미 발에 감각이 없소.
Finally you're joining your comrades-dasu.
후후, 드디어 동료하고 만나오.
I wonder where Mr. Saigo is...
사이고 씨는 어디 있을까나...
Just as you're saying, Jipangu will be wasted at this rate-gowasu.
그대가 말하는 대로 이대로는 지팡구 국에 안 좋습니다.
Mr. Saigo!
사이고 씨!
For that too, the system of the world must be changed!
그걸 위해서도 이 세상의 체제를 바꾸어야!
What-dasu?!
뭣이오?!
Then, you...
그럼 당신.
Prepare yourself, Mr. Saigo!
사이고 씨, 각오!
Mr. Saigo, who are you?!
사이고 씨, 당신이라는 자는!
You are that dango boy I saw during the day-gowasu. What are you doing, springing out from a weird place-gowasu?!
그대는 낮에 단고 군이군. 이상한 곳에서 튀어나와 뭔 짓이냐!
I thought you were a good guy, but I was surprised when I realized you are Shiranui's comrade-dasu!
나, 당신, 좋은 사람이라 생각했지만 시라누이의 동료라니 놀랐소!
J- just a moment, dango guy-gowasu. I do not get what you're talking about at all-gowasu.
자, 잠깐만, 단고 군. 난 그대가 뭔 말을 하고 있는지 전혀 모르겠다.
Are you still trying to play innocent at the last moment-dasu?! Know when to give up-dasu!
에잇, 이 마당에 와서 아직 시치미 뗄 생각이오! 깨끗히 죽지 못하는 놈이오!
Prepare yourself!
각오!
Musashi, stop!
무사시 군, 관둬라!
M- Mr. Ryoma!
료, 료마 씨!
It's been a while, Musashi.
오랜만이다, 무사시 군.
What?! So Mr. Saigo was feudal lord of Satsumania!
어? 사이고 씨는 사츠마니아의 영주였소!
You didn't look like one-dasu!
그런 높으신 분으로는 안 보였소!
I am not a lord because I wanted to be-gowasu. That's why I usually go with a light clothing-gowasu.
나도 되고 싶어서 되고 싶은 건 아니다. 그러니까 보통은 이런 가벼운 차림을 하고 있지.
But still, I am surprised to know someone that venerable is visiting Mr. Ryoma!
그래도 료마 씨한테 그런 높은 분이 방문하다니 놀랐소!
I am totally charmed by Mr. Ryoma's idea of making the new Jipangu.
난 료마 씨의 새 지팡구 국을 만드려는 덧없는 아이디어에 홀딱 반해서 말이지.
But as you know, Musashi, I am a wanted man, and I couldn't meet him that easily.
그래도, 나는 무사시 군이 아는 대로 수배자니까, 그렇게 간단히 만날 수는 없었지.
Moreover, I could meet him thanks to secret agents disguised as merchants and farmers-gowasu.
거기에 상인이나 농사꾼으로 변장한 정보원과 연락해서 겨우 만나게 된 거다.
So that was what's it about-dasu. I apologize for my discourtesy-dasu.
그랬소. 그것도 모르고 실례를 저질렀소.
It's alright, it's alright! Anybody can make mistakes-gowasu.
괜찮아, 괜찮아! 누구도 실수할 수 있지.
But still, you thought I was a comrade of Shiranui, and what did you exactly mean by that-gowasu?
그래도, 무사시 군은 아까 날 시라누이의 동료라고 했는데, 그건 어떤 뜻이었나?
It's because you dropped a paper with Shiranui's emblem on it back in afternoon, Mr. Saigo.
그러니까, 낮에 사이고 씨가 시라누이의 문장이 적힌 종이를 떨어뜨려서...
That is a key to finding Shiranui Clan-gowasu.
그건 시라누이 일족을 찾을 단서이다.
Were you looking for Shiranui Clan too-dasu?
사이고 씨도 시라누이 일족을 찾고 있었소?!
Yes. To be honest, the treasure house of my castle has been robbed by Shiranui Clan.
그래. 사실은 내 성의 금고가 시라누이 일족에게 털려서...
It seems that the stolen money has been transferred to Edotopia-gowasu.
훔친 돈이 이 에도토피아에 옮겨진 것 같다.
And I was trying to take the stolen money back, taking this opportunity of meeting Mr. Ryoma-gowasu.
그래서 나는 료마 씨와 만나는 김에 훔쳐진 돈을 찾고자 하고 있었다.
Those are unforgivable ones, especially since we're trying to make Jipangu State without disputes.
우리가 분쟁 없는 지팡구 국을 만들고자 하고 있는데 용서할 수 없는 놈들이지.
You're right. But we do not know where they are...
정말이오. 그러나 대체 어디에 있을지.
Those Shiranui Clan guys are in the warehouse at the port.
시라누이 일족이라면 항구의 창고에 있다.
Jiraiyan!
지라이얀!
You incorrigibly showed yourself again-dasu!
또 뉘우침없이 나타났겠소!
If you have time to care about me, then go to the warehouse! I don't know what'll happen to Kojirō and Senhime!
날 신경 쓸 틈이 있으면 창고에나 서둘러라! 코지로하고 센히메가 어떻게 되어도 난 모른다!
What-dasu?!
뭣이오?!
Now that I've paid back that from the daytime, farewell!
이걸로 낮에 건 갚았다. 그럼!
The warehouse at the port?
항구의 창고?
The ship to Satsumania is here!
사츠마니아 행 배가 왔다!
Great! Ship those cargo, and someone go sink these two!
좋아! 바로 짐을 실어라. 그리고 누가 이 둘을 빠뜨리고 와라!
Yessir!
예!
No, no! I don't want to sink at a place like this!
싫어싫어! 이런 곳에서 가라앉고 싶지 않아!
Let's face our death, as it can't be helped.
이렇게 된 바 조용히 죽음을 맞이합시다.
But my pride cannot forgive me from being sunken into a dirty sea like Edo Bay!
그래도 에도 만 같은 더러운 바다에 빠지는 건 내 프라이드가 용서할 수 없다!
Drop me into a beautiful sea like Hawaii, at least!
하다못해 하와이같은 아름다운 바다에 빠뜨려 줘!
Musashi! If you don't come save us here, then we'll become ghosts and haunt you!
무사시! 여기서 구하러 안 오면 귀신이 되어서 널 잡겠어!
Throw them into sea!
자, 바다에 던져라!
Yessir!
예!
Stop right there-dasu!
멈추시오!
W- who's there?!
누, 누구냐?!
The sky knows and the ground knows about your evil!
하늘이 알고 땅이 안다! 너희들의 악은!
I, Musashi, will not forgive you-dasu!
이 무사시가 용서하지 않겠소!
Musashi!
무사시!
How impudent of you! Get him!
뭘 건방지게! 잡아라!
Thank you, Musashi!
고마워, 무사시!
Don't you know what to do?! Get rid of those two!
뭘 꾸물꾸물대냐! 저 송사리같은 둘은 바로 처리해 버려라!
W- what?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
W- who's there?!
너, 너희들은 누구냐!
We are the ones to make Jipangu State free of disputes!
분쟁 없는 지팡구 국을 만드려는 자다!
Mr. Ryoma! Mr. Saigo!
료마 씨! 사이고 씨!
Don't make us laugh! We'll take you down all at once!
웃기고 있네. 다들 한꺼번에 몰아 처리해 주겠다!
Chest!
체스트!
Watch and feel! Jigen Style Shout Technique!
보고 느끼거라! 지겐류 기합술!
To think that bastards like you are in Kyushu, that makes me sad to the level of infuriating-gowasu!
네놈들 같은 놈들이 규슈에 있다고 생각하니 난 맹렬하게 슬프다!
Chest!
체스트!
Tsubamegaeshi!
츠바메가에시!
Mr. Ryoma! That warehouse is full of weapons! Do something!
료마 씨! 저 창고 안에 무기가 가득 있어! 빨리 어떻게 해!
Leave it to me!
맡기쇼!
Hooray!
만세!
Run away, run!
도망쳐라, 도망쳐!
It is a big relief that we could rescue you in time-dasu, Osenchan and Kojirō!
아, 마침 적당하게 구할 수 있어서 다행이었소, 오센짱, 코지로!
Hmph! This also is because you ate dangos quickly at the first place!
흥! 이런 꼴이 된 것도 애초에 네놈이 단고 빨리 먹기를 해서 그런 것이다!
What-dasu?!
뭣이오?!
-This is all- -That's enough, stop it!
-이것도 다- -니들 작작 좀해!
The plot of Shiranui Clan to attack Satsumania has been dealt with for now.
사츠마니아를 공격하려고 하는 시라누이 일족의 음모는 일단 쳐부수었다.
But an ill feeling is still between Musashi and Kojirō.
그렇지만 무사시와 코지로 사이에는 아직 마음의 응어리가 남아 있다.
The ship with stormy ones full of dramas aboard is heading to Kyushu.
파란만장의 일행을 태운 배는 이대로 규슈에 간다.
What will be the destiny of Musashi and others, making an inroad on the enemy?
적진에 쳐들어가는 무사시 일행의 운명은 어찌 되는가!
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
After landing to Satsumania at Kyushu, I met with a person named Satsumania, who is pretty and kind-dasu.
규슈의 사츠마니아에 상륙한 나는 히미코 씨라는 예쁘고 친절한 사람하고 만났소.
She's just like a mother-dasu!
마치 엄마같소!
But I fall into the trap of Shinarui Clan,
그러나 시라누이 일족의 함정에 빠진 나는 무슨, 진검승부의 무예 대회에서 벤케이하고 싸우게 되오!
Next story! I Become Delinquent!
다음 이야기! 나, 비뚤어지오!
It's a stormy mommy! -dasu!
질풍노도의 엄마! 이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
I
나
Become Delinquent
비뚤어지오
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!